<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://kindmetrics.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://kindmetrics.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><updated>2020-08-30T06:20:59+00:00</updated><id>https://kindmetrics.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kindmetrics</title><subtitle>Simple privacy-focused website analytics</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Why open source matter for privacy analytics</title><link href="https://kindmetrics.io/blog/why-open-source-matter-for-privacy-analytics" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why open source matter for privacy analytics"/><published>2020-06-23T07:15:23+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-23T07:15:23+00:00</updated><id>https://kindmetrics.io/blog/why-open-source-matter-for-privacy-analytics</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kindmetrics.io/blog/why-open-source-matter-for-privacy-analytics">&lt;p&gt;Open source has existed for some time now. It is also starting to become mainstream, which is great. But it has even started becoming a bit of a gray area, with services going in different directions to feel they have the right to call themselves privacy-friendly. As a founder of the new privacy-focused analytics service, Kindmetrics, I know from own experience.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;auditing&quot;&gt;Auditing&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;You should not have to take someone on their word that they will take good care of your data. It will like in a movie—how often does everything end up fine when a character says that they should be trusted? You should have the right to see for yourself if they stand by privacy norms and handle data, both yours and your visitors’, as safely as is possible.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Trust only yourself.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;push-the-project-in-the-right-direction&quot;&gt;Push the project in the right direction&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you have audited the project and seen some mistakes or have ideas to do things better, or if you can’t code, you can have a feature request. Feel free to join and help push the project forward in the direction you want. That is part of open source. If you need something and know how to code, you can always build it and ask to add it to the project. They should align with the idealogy and plans of the project; those usually exist in the description or the issues.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Take Kindmetrics as an example. Kindmetrics probably has bugs or some miscalculations on the fundamentals, and I am always open to a bug report or a fix by some Kindmetrics user. I cannot be perfect, and open-source help makes the project better for you and your visitors.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;but-if-they-can-self-host-it-then-we-wont-get-the-money&quot;&gt;But if they can self-host it, then we won’t get the money.&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;That rationale is typically what most companies or people use to justify their decision not to open source. Take Fathom, a competitor to Kindmetrics, as an example. They have an episode on their podcast where they explain why they decided not to make the new version of their service open source because “paid users have to come first.”&lt;a href=&quot;https://usefathom.com/podcast/opensource&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Of course, I agree with them, but I don’t see this as a valid point to not do open source. Support handles well in open source as well. You can easily handle small issues and support without taking a lot of time. If someone needs more significant help, say, setting up the service, I can offer a support package with time-based or fixed pricing. I value my time, and many open-source services also do this.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If it is the same code base, paid users and open-source users will most likely touch the same bugs, so you will prioritize those that have the most impact. So indirectly you will help both. Kindmetrics is also using docker for deployment and for publishing the service, making it easy to have straightforward releases and deployments.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You won’t lose customers as well. Those who self-host would most likely not pay for your service anyway. If they won’t, let them use Kindmetrics anyway to build a relationship and make them happy with Kindmetrics instead. They could become ambassadors for Kindmetrics that way.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. You can check &lt;a href=&quot;https://kindmetrics.io&quot;&gt;Kindmetrics, simple privacy website analytics&lt;/a&gt;. The GitHub repo is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kindmetrics/kindmetrics&quot;&gt;github.com/kindmetrics/kindmetrics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Håkan Nylén</name><email>hakan@dun.se</email></author><summary type="html">Open source has existed for some time now. It is also starting to become mainstream, which is great. But it has even started becoming a bit of a gray area, with services going in different directions to feel they have the right to call themselves privacy-friendly. As a founder of the new privacy-focused analytics service, Kindmetrics, I know from own experience.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why I built my own Analytics tool</title><link href="https://kindmetrics.io/blog/why-i-built-own-analytics" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why I built my own Analytics tool"/><published>2020-06-06T07:06:13+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-06T07:06:13+00:00</updated><id>https://kindmetrics.io/blog/why-i-built-own-analytics</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kindmetrics.io/blog/why-i-built-own-analytics">&lt;p&gt;Website analytics is on the rise right now. It exists a lot of them already, some that have been here for a while, like Google Analytics, Matomo (formerly Piwik) and new ones like Fathom and Plausible.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I have also seen many that are under developing. So it is even more coming.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So why did I start building my own Analytics service? I felt that most of them had most of the things I need but I felt I couldn’t trust the services they were depending on. Some use Amazon, others Netlify. I as European want to have some that use European services when needed, and if it couldn’t, at least have the servers based on European soil.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I got also a bit sad that most of these privacy-focused analytics also let the user opt-out from respecting things like Do Not Track. Which for me makes no sense. As an privacy-focused analytics should just respect the visitor’s privacy if they ask to not be tracked to not track them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;My analytics service, Kindmetrics, force respecting DNT, it won’t send a track call to the server if DNT is enabled in the javascript code. Soon that will also be checked on server-side. Kindmetrics is using Digitalocean but is explicit only using the datacenter in Germany.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I use Mailjet, which is Paris-based, here others use Mailgun, Sendgrid or Amazon own one. Being privacy-focused but let big companies handle your user’s mails are a bit contradicting. It is important to respect the visitors and your user’s privacy.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I have also announced I won’t use a CDN on the app domain of it (I use Github pages for the landing page, which use fastly) - all API calls will not pass through some third party at my analytics. Others use Cloudflare or other ones.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Kindmetrics are also open source so you can check the code yourself, so you can trust what is going in the code. If you are not sure you can check it out. Included to that I have also opened up my todo and what is next. You can always add your own issues or make own changes if you want.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I hope you guys would like to try Kindmetrics out, you can give &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@kindmetrics.io&quot;&gt;feedback here&lt;/a&gt;. Feel free to ask any questions&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Håkan Nylén</name><email>hakan@dun.se</email></author><summary type="html">Website analytics is on the rise right now. It exists a lot of them already, some that have been here for a while, like Google Analytics, Matomo (formerly Piwik) and new ones like Fathom and Plausible.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kindmetrics is open source</title><link href="https://kindmetrics.io/blog/kindmetrics-is-open-source" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kindmetrics is open source"/><published>2020-06-04T13:52:31+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-04T13:52:31+00:00</updated><id>https://kindmetrics.io/blog/kindmetrics-is-open-source</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kindmetrics.io/blog/kindmetrics-is-open-source">&lt;p&gt;Kindmetrics is open source since yesterday. What does that mean for you? I will tell you below.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can check the code by yourself to be sure that will handle the data from your visitors in a good way. If you are not technical you can trmet that others that are will check and approve or disapproved the code.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can also help push Kindmetrics forward in maybe the road you want Kindmetrics to take. You can get things done faster.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And most important, an total transparent follow of a project you will like. You can see what changes we do and when we did them. All those bugs we fixed and also those we created. It can’t be more transparent than this.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can also deploy your own server of kindmetrics and won’t need to pay me or letting me host your data. It will be safest for you that way and some would like that way more than paying me, And I am okay with that.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Check up the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.github.com/kindmetrics/kindmetrics&quot;&gt;repo here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Håkan Nylén</name><email>hakan@dun.se</email></author><summary type="html">Kindmetrics is open source since yesterday. What does that mean for you? I will tell you below.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kindmetrics is in open beta!</title><link href="https://kindmetrics.io/blog/kindmetrics-is-in-open-beta" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kindmetrics is in open beta!"/><published>2020-06-03T13:31:13+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-03T13:31:13+00:00</updated><id>https://kindmetrics.io/blog/kindmetrics-is-in-open-beta</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kindmetrics.io/blog/kindmetrics-is-in-open-beta">&lt;p&gt;Kindmetrics is out in open beta!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Wanted to say that for 20 days now. That’s right, I have been working on kindmetrics for 20 days. With that I have been pushing commits almost every day. It have been hard but I am happy to finally have it in open beta.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I got inspired by &lt;em&gt;Simple analytics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Fathom&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Piwik/Matomo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Plausible&lt;/em&gt;. I tried to put everything I felt was good and optimized the privacy even more than they did. I think that is important to know. They are based on un-EU countries, they use third party that are either bad on privacy or in America that is not so good on privacy. Kindmetrics is EU-based, have the servers on EU soil (Germany) and only use eu-based third parties, like Mailjet.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So Kindmetrics is stepping up the game! I hope you will like the service.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So what can I do on Kindmetrics now?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can do:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;See total uniques, total page views and bounce rate&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;most visited Pages&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;top referrers&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;top countries&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;top devices, browser and OS.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Detailed referrer with links to page that links to you&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Detailed country page with big map of the world, with marked countries that have visited you.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;You will be using all above right now. And for now it is free. Only thing I am asking as a return is feedback and bug reports. In that way we can move forward and do following in my current todo:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What you can do soon:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Email reports to custom emails and yourself&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Own domain for the javascript file&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;And more to come&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;pay for Kindmetrics&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Feel free to come with ideas for making Kindmetrics even better!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I hope you will enjoy Kindmetrics as much as I did making it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Håkan Nylén</name><email>hakan@dun.se</email></author><summary type="html">Kindmetrics is out in open beta!</summary></entry></feed>